Guide to the Postdoctoral Office, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Postdoctoral Office, Yale University, records
1984-2005
RU 917
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
29
The records consist of files on personnel, postdoctoral fellows, and associates and research facilities maintained by the Central Campus branch of the Yale Postdoctoral Office.
Yale University. Postdoctoral Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 3-D (YRG 3-D), Records documenting academic support functions at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Postdoctoral Office, 2002-2009.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
Established in 2002, the Yale Postdoctoral Office consists of two branches, the Central Campus branch and the School of Medicine branch. Its purpose is to assist postdoctoral fellows and associates at Yale by processing admissions, tracking postdoctoral progress, and providing orientation about Yale, New Haven, Connecticut and surrounding areas
Scope and Contents
The records consist of files on personnel, postdoctoral fellows, and associates and research facilities maintained by the Central Campus branch of the Yale Postdoctoral Office.
Universities and colleges -- Graduate work; Yale University -- Funds and scholarships; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Postdoctoral Office
- Records of visiting fellows, 1982-2002; Accession 2003-A-036
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2037
  - Afro-American Studies, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Studies, 1985-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anthropology, 1986-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Applied Physics, 1985-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Astronomy, 1986-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chemistry, 1985-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 8)
  - Classics, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Comparative Literature, 1998-2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Computer Science, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - East Asian Lang. & Lit., 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Economics, 1985-2002 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 17)
  - English, 1985-2002 (Box 1, Folder 20 - 21)
  - Forestry, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Geology & Geophysics, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - History of Art, 1986-2002 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - History of Science, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - History, 1984-2002 (Box 2, Folder 26 - 27)
  - ISPS, 1986-2002 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - ISS, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Latin American Studies, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Mathematics, 1984-2002 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Mechanical Eng, 1985-2001 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - MCDB, 1985-2002 (Box 2, Folder 33 - 34)
  - Philosophy, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Physics, 1999-2002 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Political Science, 1984-2001 (Box 2, Folder 37 - 38)
  - Psychology, 1986-2002 (Box 2, Folder 39 - 41)
  - Religious Studies, 1982-2002
  - Slavic Language & Literature, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Sociology, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 43 - 44)
  - Statistics, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Whitney Humanities Ctr, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Women's & Gender Studies, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - YCIAS, 1984-2002 (Box 4, Folder 48 - 53)
- Records of research affiliates, 1977-2002; Accession 2003-A-037
  - American Studies, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anthropology, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Astronomy, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chemical Engineering, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chemistry, 1985-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Classics, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Computer Science, 1987-2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Economics, 1998-2002 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
  - EEB, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - English, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - French, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Geology & Geophysics, 1985-2001 (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
  - History, 1983-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ISPS, 1977-2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Linguistics, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mathematics, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - MCDB, 1987-2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Near Eastern Language & Civilization, 1984-2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Philosophy, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Physics, 1986-2001 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Psychology, 1985-2002 (Box 1, Folder 26 - 27)
  - Russian & European Studies, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Spanish & Portuguese, 1986-2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - YCIAS, 1984-2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Records of postdoctoral fellows, 1981-1988; Accession 2003-A-038
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - A, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - D, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - F, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - G, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - H, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - I, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - J, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - K, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - L, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - M, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - N, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - O, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - P, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - R, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - S, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - T, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - V, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - W, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Z, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Personnel records, 1997-2004; Accession 2005-A-189
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2079
- Personnel records, 2004-2005; Accession 2006-A-144
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2081
- Personnel records, 2005-2006; Accession 2008-A-006
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2082.
- Personnel records, 1945-2007; Accession 2008-A-144; 4; (4 boxes)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2083
- Postdoctoral personnel records, 2007-2008; Accession 2009-A-166
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2084